Guide to the New York Wine & Grape Foundation records, 1968-2004.
New York Wine & Grape Foundation records}
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York Wine & Grape Foundation records, 1968-2004.
6707
New York Wine & Grape Foundation.
37 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Financial records, Photographs, Printed material, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records documenting the work of the Mew York Wine and Grape Foundation.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
New York Wine & Grape Foundation (NYWGF) is a not-for-profit trade association of the New York wine and grape industries that is charged with promoting the products of the New York grape growing and wine producing industries and funding research relevant to these industries.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records documenting the work of the Foundation including promotion, legislative work, funded research, and trade shows and conferences. Includes information on area wineries and the Uncork New York! campaign. Many items showing the involvements of President Jim Tresize. Also papers regarding other groups such as the New York State Wine Grape Growers and The New York Wine Council.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York Wine & Grape Foundation.
Subjects:
Grape industry -- New York (State); Wine and wine making -- New York (State); Wine -- Marketing.; Liquor laws.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also collection #6695 Box 4 for oversize items including advertising proofs for NYWGF ad campaigns.
A brief history of the New York Wine & Grape Foundation was published in Wine East volume 22 number 3, September - October 1994, under the title "How a Foundation Helped Uncork New York" by Hudson Cattell. A copy is available in the accession folder.
NOTES
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
SERIES LIST
Series I. Administrative Records
Boxes 1-8
Series II. Agricultural Organizations, Publications & Research
Boxes 9-11
Series III. Organizations
Box 12
Series IV. Wineries
Boxes 13-15
Series V. Trade Shows
Box 16
Series VI. Legislation
Boxes 17-21
Series VII. Public Relations
Box 22
Series VIII. Marketing Research
Boxes 23-25
Series IX. Newspaper and Press
Boxes 26-31
Series X. Events
Boxes 32-37
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Administrative Records
  - Daily diary, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Daily diary, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Daily diary, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Steno notebooks, ca. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chronological files, January 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chronological files, February 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chronological files, March 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronological files, April 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronological files, May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chronological files, June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chronological files, July 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chronological files, August 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chronological files, September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chronological files, October 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chronological files, November 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chronological files, December 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chronological files, January 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chronological files, February 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chronological files, March 1, 1983-March, 17 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chronological files, March 18, 1983-March 31, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chronological files, April 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chronological files, May 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chronological files, June 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chronological files, July 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chronological files, August 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chronological files, September 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chronological files, October 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chronological files, April 1, 1984-April 13, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chronological files, April 14, 1984-April 30, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chronological files, May 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chronological files, June 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chronological files, July 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chronological files, August 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chronological files, September 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chronological files, October 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chronological files, November 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chronological files, December 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chronological files, January 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chronological files, February 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chronological files, March 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chronological files, April 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chronological files, May 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chronological files, June 1, 1985-June14, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chronological files, June 15, 1985-June 30,1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Chronological files, July 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chronological files, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chronological files, September 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chronological files, October 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chronological files, November 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chronological files, December 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chronological files, January 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chronological files, February 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chronological files, March 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chronological files, April 1, 1986-April 14, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chronological files, April 15, 1986-April 30, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chronological files, May 1, 1986-May7, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chronological files, May 8, 1986-May 31, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chronological files, June 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Chronological files, July 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chronological files, August 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Chronological files, September 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Chronological files, October 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chronological files, November 1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Chronological files, December 1, 1986 - December 10, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Chronological files, December 11, 1986-December 31, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and communications, 1969-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, S.C. Zeke Mendall, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, growers, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, growers, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence received, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - New York Farm Bureau, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - New York farm Bureau, legislative contracts, 1969-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Commissioner Joseph Gerace, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Howard H. Kimball, July 16,1980-January 1,1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Howard H. Kimball, January 1980-June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Legislation, 1968, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Legislative reports, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, membership lists, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, membership lists, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, membership lists, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, membership drive, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - New York Grape Grower, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Publicity, ca. 1969-1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Questionnaire responses, New York State Assembly, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Questionnaire responses, New York State Senate, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Elaine Ryan, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Charles Lamont (Monty) Stamp, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Monty Stamp, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Jim Tresize correspondence, notes, speeches, and resume, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jim Tresize correspondence and notes, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jim Tresize speeches, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Juanita Spence, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Juanita Spence, Paul Smith's College, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Juanita Spence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Juanita Spence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Juanita Spence, Manager, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, New York Times, 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Media ideas, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New York Wine and Grape Foundation formation, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Founding documents, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 501(c)3 information (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Balance sheets, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Balance sheets, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Membership proposal, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Board of directors, correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Board of directors, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - First Year Promotion and Research Recommendations - A Perspective, New York Wine Council to Board of Directors, New York Wine and Grape Foundation, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Foundation administration, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Foundation mailing list requests, all wineries, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Foundation mailing list requests, legislators, media, and organizations, ca. 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Foundation mailing list requests, all growers, ca. 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Foundation mailing list requests, consumers, ca.1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Foundation mailing list requests, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Members, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Jim Tresize notes, financial and legal, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Board of directors, correspondence from Jim Tresize, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Board of directors, correspondence from Jim Tresize, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board of directors, correspondence from Jim Tresize, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Board of directors, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Strategic plan, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Finance and membership, ca. 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Foundation documents off computer, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vendors, ca. 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Board of directors, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Board of directors, correspondence, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Board of directors, correspondence, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Board of directors, correspondence, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Annual meeting, March 2-3, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Annual meeting, presentations, March 2-3, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Beverly Barbour correspondence, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Accounting, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Research contracts, State of New York Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Research contracts, State of New York Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Hank Boerner, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Board of directors, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Board of directors, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Board of directors, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Board of directors, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Plaques, board of directors, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Table grape meeting, January 19, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Annual meeting, February 21-23, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Annual meeting, February 21-23, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Larry Emminger, Jim Tresize, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Jim Tresize, budget, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Budgets, long-range, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Board of directors, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Board of directors, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Board of directors, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Annual meeting, Niagara Falls, March 8-9, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Annual meeting, Niagara Falls, March 8-9, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Board of directors, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Annual meeting, Albany, NY, March 6-7, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Annual meeting, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Annual meeting, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Annual report and financial statements, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Board of directors, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Board of directors, correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Board meeting, Canandaigua, NY, August 22, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Board meeting, August 20, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting minutes, October 25, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting, Albany, NY, June 2, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting, Albany, NY, March 6, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting, Kenmore, NY, June 7, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Board meeting, Geneva, NY, August 16, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Board meeting, Albany, NY, October 25, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Board meeting, Rochester, NY, January 16, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Board meeting, Albany, NY, March 1, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Accounting meeting, Geneva, NY, March 15, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Board meeting, Westfield, NY, June 6, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Board meeting, Glenora Wine Cellars, August 21, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Board meeting, Albany, NY, November 20, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Award nominations due, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Annual meeting, Rochester, NY, January 14-15, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Board meeting, March 4, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Board meeting, March 4, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Board meeting, Buffalo, NY, June 4, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Board meeting, November 19, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Board meeting, November 19, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Board meeting, Glenora Wine Cellars, August 21, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Budget request, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Conference call, J. Finkle et al., February 26, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Board of Directors meeting, March 9, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Board meeting, June 10, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Board meeting, August 20, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Board of Directors conference call, January 18, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Board meeting, March 3, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Board meeting, March 24, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Board meeting, August 26, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Board meeting, November 21-22, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Series II. Agricultural Organizations, Publications & Research
  - New York Agricultural Statistics Service (NYASS) Crop Survey Reports, 1975-1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    The New York Agricultural Statistics Service was the result of a cooperative agreement between the NYS Department of Agriculture and Markets and the National Agricultural Statistics Service of USDA to provide details about current trends in agriculture.
  - NYASS Crop Survey Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NYASS Crop Survey Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - NY Crop Reporting Service, 1984-1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Special reports of temperature and precipitation throughout New York state.
  - NYASS Orchard and Vineyard Surveys, 1985-2000 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - NY State Department of Agriculture Statistics, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - NYS Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Grape production, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Cooperative Extension, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cooperative Extension, 1985-1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension, Schuyler County, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - New York Farm Bureau, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - New York Farm Bureau, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - New York Farm Bureau, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - New York Farm Bureau, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - New York State Horticultural Society, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Yates County Farm Bureau, 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Wine and Grape Growers Association, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - California Association of Winegrape Growers, ca. 1970's (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - California Association of Winegrape Growers, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - California Association of Winegrape Growers, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - California Association of Winegrape Growers, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - California Association of Winegrape Growers, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Maryland Grape Growers Association, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Minnesota Grape Growers Association, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - New Mexico Vine and Wine Society, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Research, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Research, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Research, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Research Proposals, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Research, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Research Proposals and Progress Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Research, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Wine Advisory Committee, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Wine Advisory Committee, Research Proposals, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Research, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Penn State Contract, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Wine and Grape Foundation Project Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Summary Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Research Proposals, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Geneva Experimental Station, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Grape production research fund, Rochester NY, January 15-17, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, February 15, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, August 13, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, February 2, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, July 17, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, January 12. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, February 5, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, February 10, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Grape Production Research Fund Meeting, August 17, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Funded Research Projects, 1986-1991 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Grape Research News, 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - New Research, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Publications and Newsletters, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Publications, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Empire State Food Service News, July 1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Grape Growers & Winery News, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Finger Lakes Association, 1981-1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Gomberg Report, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Vineyard Post, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Vineyard Post, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Winegrape Press, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Winegrape Press, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Alcohol Education Curriculum Guides, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - New York State Wine Country, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - A Study of Demand for Wine in the US by Lynn Sakala, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Wine: From Vine to Glass (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Allied Organizations, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - American Dairy Association and Dairy Council, Inc, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - AIWF (NYC Events), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - American Wine Society, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Association of American Vintners (AAV), 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Association of American Vintners (AAV), AAV wine brief, 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Aware Fingerlakes Forum, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Finger Lakes Regional Economic Development Council, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - WNDA, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - NYS Agricultural Society, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Series III. Organizations
  - New York Association of Wine Producers, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - New York Association of Wine Producers, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - New York Wine Institute, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Wine Institute, 1986-1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Wine Institute, 1979-1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, Inc. Executive Council, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - NYWGF Newsletter, 1987-1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, Inc, NY Wine, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - NYS Wine Grape Growers, NY Wine Council Brochures, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers/New York Wine Council Mail Data, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers/New York Wine Council, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers/New York Wine CouncilBudget, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, Inc. Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers Mail Data, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - New York State Wine Grape Growers, Inc. request for proposals, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - California Wine Newsletter, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - New York State Agriculture Reports, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Canada Wines, 1969-1986 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Wine Excise Taxes, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - NYSWGG Grape Juice Files, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - NYSWGG History, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Irate Letters (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Italian Wine, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Gomberg, Louis, 1985-1990 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Grape Vine Quality Control, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Grape Production Study, NYSGG, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Finger Lakes Grape Varieties, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Grape Pricing Laws, 1974-1987 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Grape Co-ops, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Lake Erie - Niagara Mohawk Environmental Studies, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Legal Files, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Legal Files, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Goldwyn, Craig. Files, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Goldberg, Howard. Files, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - New York City Wine-Grape Market, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - NYS Advisory Council on Agriculture, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - NYS Institute/ Tourism Development, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - NYS Budget, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - NYS Farm-City Council, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - NYS Food Merchants Association, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - NYS Food Processors, March 1987 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Nicaragua News, April 25, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - No Alcohol Wines, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Wine and Health Files, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Albany Wine Editorial, December 9, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Alcohol Server Liability Document, August 1988 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Leon Adams Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 47)
- Series IV. Wineries
  - Barry Wine Company, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Baldwin Vineyards, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Brotherhood Winery, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Benmarl, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Brimstone Hill Vineyards, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Canadaigua Wine Company, Inc., 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Casa Larga Vineyards, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Cascade Mountain Vineyards, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cayuga Wine Trail, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Chateau Esperanza Winery, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Chateau Georges, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Clinton Vineyards Inc, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Cottage Vineyards, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Crown Regal Wine Cellars, 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Eagle Crest Vineyards, Inc., 1984 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Finger Lakes Wine Cellars, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Four Chimneys Farm Winery, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Glenora Wine Cellars, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Gold Seal Vineyards Inc., 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Great Western Winery, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Hargrave Vineyards, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Heron Hill (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Johnson Estate, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Joseph Victori Wines, Inc, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Knapp Vineyards, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Lac Domaine Wine Cellars, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Lakeshore Winery, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Lenz (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Lucas Vineyards, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Magnanni Vineyards, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - McGregor Vineyard, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Merritt Estate Winery Inc, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Monarch Wine Co, Inc, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 33)